David Lomas Gonzalez

Jocotepec, Jalisco, Mexico david.lomas0712@gmail.com Linkedin/in/david-lomas-gonzalez-691488322

Summary

As a Senior Full Stack Developer, I'm keenly interested in algorithm-level efficiency and has experience working both with front-end and back-end technologies.

React, Angular, Web3 and Node.js, PHP, .Net enthusiast. Spending most of time in the tech community.

Education

Instituto Tecnológico de Tlajomulco Jalisco, 2011 - 2015

Gained Bachelor's degree of Computer Science

Experience

Full Stack Web3 Developer, TOKENTRAXX

Oct, 2021 - Aug, 2024

The main stage for music in Web3. Connecting artists and fans to mint the sound of a decentralized future

- Created the shared component library using **React**, **TailwindCss**, **Storybook**, **Webpack** and published it into **Gitlab** npm package registry.
- Wrote a doc for using and updating the shared component library in **Confluence**.
- Created a user interface using **Figma** design with user-friendly multi-step form using Typescript, **React**, **Redux** and **Next.js**.
- Designed and built infrastructure for **Web3** wallets integration includes the ability to directly connect to external wallet providers, enabling seemless onboarding of crypto native alongside the social login.
- Designed and implemented a new, high-security architecture to protect the wallet against attacks via open source dependencies.
- Created some API endpoints to integrate music NFT mint, list, buy, sell and auction functions using **Node.js** in backend.
- Also created backend APIs to upload the NFT to AWS S3 bucket and Arweave.
- Integrated with TRAXX Studios, an interconnected network of fully customizable NFT marketplaces.
- Implemented Live video conferencing & collaboration functions using **WebRTC**.
- Created an admin panel to manage user accounts and their actions using Angular, RxJS and Nest.js.
- Improved the app performance for efficient data handling and manipulation using GraphQL.
- Implemented interaction with Ethereum Smart contracts using Typescipt, Web3, Solidity, Polymesh.
- Built the infrastructure for the end-to-end testing using Cypress.
- Implemented **Microservices** architecture using **Docker** and **Kubernetes**, improving deployment flexibility, and enabling efficient scaling of services.
- Worked on Agile SDLC, Scrum Methodology to practice-based methodology for modeling and documentation of software based systems.

David Lomas Gonzalez

Jocotepec, Jalisco, Mexico david.lomas0712@gmail.com Linkedin/in/david-lomas-gonzalez-691488322

Software Developer, ARENA

May 2018 – Sep 2021

Arena is a software startup developing the next generation of engagement tools powered by first party data

- Improved efficiency of existing solutions and fixing bugs for stable in end-user experience.
- Created components library for shared components, editable tables, and utilities using **React**, **Typescript**, **Tailwind CSS**, **Storybook** and **Webpack**.
- Created visually appealing and user-friendly interfaces by building responsive pages on frontend frameworks such as **React** and **Angular**, and utilizing **Tailwind CSS**, **JS/TypeScript**, and other tools.
- Consulted regularly with customers for building user-friendly web application and contributed on revenue growth.
- Built a **RESTful** web service using **PHP**, **Laravel**, **MySQL**, and **Redis**, optimizing them for dynamic usage across mobile and web applications.
- Scraped data using **Python/Django** and created a new individual frontend to display live blogs.
- Created and Implemented Live Chat and Live Blog using WebRTC and Socket.IO.
- Developed and designed a responsive and efficient search system using **Elasticsearch**.
- Implemented a read-write split and a master-slave sync system, utilizing **AWS** for web service deployment and website hosting, with **Apache Kafka** as a messaging system.
- Performed code review and PHPUnit tests and estimated tasks and applied clean code practices.
- Designed technical tasks for interviews and assisted in onboarding new team members.

Full Stack Developer, Myclubs

Feb, 2016 - Apr, 2018

The largest corporate fitness provider in Austria and Switzerland.

- Created a microservices-based architecture, leveraging **Azure PaaS** offerings such as **Azure Functions**, **Azure SQL**, and **CosmosDB** to ensure scalability and reliability for the corporate fitness platform.
- Implemented a modern, responsive frontend solution using **React**, focusing on performance and maintainability, and created and integrated the **ASP.NET Core** backend API with frontend, ensuring it was scalable, secure, and well-documented.
- Developed custom **C#** components and services to handle complex business logic and integrate with various external systems and data sources.
- Integrated the system with **Azure Notification Hubs** and **Azure Event Hub** to handle automated marketing flyers, fitness challenges, and wellness notifications, ensuring scalability and reliability.
- Designed a custom reporting dashboard using **Power BI**, providing rich, interactive reporting capabilities for the corporate clients to analyze employee participation, program effectiveness, and ROI.
- Leveraged the ASP.NET Core Identity framework to implement secure user authentication and authorization, and integrated the system with Azure Active Directory for seamless single sign-on (SSO) functionality.

David Lomas Gonzalez

Jocotepec, Jalisco, Mexico david.lomas0712@gmail.com

Linkedin/in/david-lomas-gonzalez-691488322

- Implemented Test Driven Development (TDD) using the **NUnit** Framework for unit testing and ability to load, explore and execute tests.
- Contributed enhancing team culture by adopting several methodologies like retrospective meeting.

Skills

- Javascript / Typescript
- React | Redux | Next
- Angular | RxJS | NgRX
- Node.js | Express.js | Nest.js | Fastify
- PHP | Laravel, Symfony
- Python | Django, C++, C#, Go
- .NET, .NET Core, ASP.NET, ASP.NET Core, ADO.NET, WCF, WPF, Web Forms, Win Forms, Entity Framework, Blazor, BizTalk
- Rust, Solidity | Web3 | Ether
- OpenZeppelin, Truffle
- BTC | ETH | BSC | Polygon
- IPFS
- Avalanche | Solana
- SQL, MySQL, Postgresql
- MongoDB, Redis
- GraphQL
- Swagger

- Apache Cassandra, Kafka, Elasticsearch
- Jest, Mocha, PHPUnit, NUnit
- Karma, Jasmine, Cypress
- Material-UI, Anti-UI, Chakra-ui, PrimeNG
- Storybook
- RESTful API, Google APIs
- WebRTC
- gRPC
- NPM
- AWS (Dynomodb, S3 bucket, Lambda, SQS, EC2), Azure
- Nginx
- Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Maven, Terraform
- Git, GitLab
- Jira, Notion, Trello
- Subversion (SVN)
- Scrum